發現。
作為。
立法會主席。
主席， on behalf of the Public Accounts Committee.
第一個問題：跟進行動，就公屋租賃房屋的水樣檢測，就鉛。
on maintenance and safety-related improvements on public rental housing flats.
For lead and the management of asbestos-containing materials in the rental estates.
石禮謙議員會就政府賬目委員會第六十七A號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙議員。
以減緩這危機的影響，因為接觸鉛可能會對租户的健康產生負面影響。
The audit report touches on several aspects of housing department's maintenance and safety-related improvement programmes of the public rental housing flats.
我有榮譽呈交我們的報告號碼67A，which contains our conclusions and recommendations on Chapter One of the Directors of Audit Report Number 67。
The housing authority, with the housing department as its executive arm, develops and implements a public housing programme to meet the housing needs of low-income families.
as at 31 March 2016, there were more than 750,000 public rental flats to cater for the housing needs of around 2.1 million people.
proper maintenance and improvement programme is essential for maintaining a healthy and safe environment for the tenants as well as for other stakeholders such as workers, commercial tenants and housing department staff. The committee has taken longer time to.
Study in details the various issues reviewed in the audit report and the evidence provided by the witnesses. Two main issues that I would like to report today, Mr. President, and they are the follow-up actions on water sampling tests.
在7月2015，，被發現有過量的鎘存在於部分公營出租屋苑的飲用水中。委員會承認，房屋署與其他相關政府部門和機構已採取及時行動。
發展。
反映該部門的Poor Governance。
這是 evidences by the absence of minutes.
委員會敦促房屋部門採取措施，以確保分鐘。
given that, after all, he is such an experienced senior public officer.
The committee also expresses grave dismay and finds it inexcusable that the director of housing.
for the first seven interdepartmental meetings held between 20th July to 7th August 2015.
And was contradictory to the principles of maintaining proper records and keeping information open and transparent.
Housing department is also urged to strengthen data validation, so that information provided to the public is accurate and complete.
to review the water sampling test results and the omission of two non-compliant samples when reporting the water test results to the public.
Meeting notes on all discussion in respect of water sampling matters, as well as other important matters, are maintained to support evidence-based decision making.
The committee is not convinced and finds it unacceptable by the director of housing's explanation that he did not realise the need to prepare minutes for the meetings until the eighth meeting.
However, the committee has noted some unexplainable activities of housing department in handling of this crisis that have deviated from the established procedure and practices that constitute good governance.
Being chairman of the interdepartmental meetings and subject officer in handling the crisis did not fulfil his role in ensuring proper records of relevant deliberations and decisions. For the seven meetings were maintained.
委員會表達了極度的擔憂和強烈的不滿，並認為這是不可接受的。關於房屋部門的疏忽和缺乏協調、管理及處理有關水樣檢測的資訊，有關公共租住房屋的態度。
Now I turn to the second issue, the management of asbestos-containing materials in public rental housing estates. On the subject of asbestos, the committee finds it appalling and inexcusable that Housing Department has not taken adequate and effective safeguards to.
嗯。
Protect tenants.
政府法案。
公共租賃屋邨。
Mr. President, I like to touch on the other minor issues.
所有bestos含有的材料應該被妥善標示。
最後，我 wish to record my appreciation of the contribution made by members of the committee.
委員會的結論和建議，這些主題已經在報告中詳細説明。
Furthermore, information on the location of of abasters containing materials is not easily available to the public.
機制維持及更新這些相關紀錄，應審視，以確保它們準確及完整。
workers and users of premises for the potential hazards of carcinogenic asbestos-containing materials in public rental estates.
This is shown by the housing department's past practice of not labelling some asbestos-containing materials, which was contrary to the guidelines issued by the Environment Protection Department.
委員會敦促和警告房屋部門採取措施，以確保所有租客、工人和利益相關者都充分了解廢棄物堆填區的所在地點，透過有效的宣傳渠道。
Our gratitude goes to the witnesses who attended the hearings, helped by the committee. I would like to express our gratitude to the director of audit and his colleagues for their unfailing support, and last but not the least, for the secretariat for their hard work. Thank you, Mr. President.
The committee is surprised and finds it unacceptable about housing department's poor record management relating to asbestos-containing materials. No accurate and up-to-date information is provided for estate management staff in their duty inspections and monitoring.
The other report has also touched upon other issues which affect the safety and well-being of the public rental housing tenants, such as flat maintenance of public rental housing flats, replacement of laundry pole holders, and enhancing fire safety of old.
本會現在恢復二零一七年撥款條例草案嘅二讀辯論。